you know so this Vim thing Vim this Vim
thing that we've been using the first I
mean we don't need to talk about whether
you should use Vim or not we talked
about that in a different video now we
need to talk about how to set Vim up in
the terminal and this unfortunately is
not really explained anywhere so um and
I I want to be really clear here we're
talking about them not neovim not bi
even even though it's similar and of
course not Ed or any of those others
so uh I just want to be really clear on
that particular point I'm not
particularly bashing neim or any of
those other things
today uh but I think it's important that
you know that the the reason I say that
is because people site one of the
advantages of neovim is that it has a
much cleaner easier happier
configuration I disagree completely but
that's what they say so if you are
coming to this video because you want to
set up them and you think that the video
is going to work for neim I need to make
sure you know that that's not true right
um Neo as far as I know actually I could
be wrong on this but NE I think neim
configuration files uh are
incompatible uh with Vim configuration
files um and uh neovim people love to
hate on something called Vim script
which is the language of that we use in
the vmrc file to this video is not going
to break down the content of the bmrc
file that is a separate video probably
sep several separate videos um this is
this video is going to tell you where
all the files go and I'll suggest to you
one way that you can make it easy to set
up these files anywhere uh relatively
quickly so whether you're building a
container or you're setting up a desktop
or server or whatever you can just go in
there and clone your dot files and then
use that there is a separate video
however about how to set up and your dot
files and why you might want to do that
um and so that I think that sets up
everything for this video um at the
beginning the only thing we're going to
talk about in this video is where are
the configuration files for viim where
do they go you know uh we we will talk
briefly about how to install Bim if you
haven't done that already it's super
easy uh on on a buntu we're not going to
talk about the other distro that they're
not included in the Boost um you can
figure that out it's not hard and um
then we talk about where these files Go
how you can set them up how you can
reuse them and stuff okay um again this
is very personalized to the things that
I think are important for them
everybody's got different opinions
that's what's so great about Linux and
and Unix is that you can have different
opinions you can you can configure that
crap out of it to make it the way you
want it and that is fine for you um so
I'm just going to share some this with
you right now so the first thing uh to
find here I'm going to turn this off
because we I don't want to obate
that um so so so here is uh my DOT files
there's again there's another video on
this so this is a do repo I this is my
organization why I put it under Capital
repos is explained elsewhere um and so
under here under the dot repo there is a
Vim directory and inside of that
directory there's a read me here that
talks about it uh you know this is uh
why not bate plugins um because they
suck okay so if you I mean you can read
that that's kind of over your head if
you're a beginner boost person um the
setup script is super important but and
this is going to kind of give an
overview of where all the files go and
why oh look Shell Shell Che is is mad at
me oh I didn't okay shell check is mad
as M as mad at me all right I'm going to
fix that I guess I'll have to F
whoopsy use
why okay well I'm not doing that right
now how about we just use bash
instead how about
that because everything I install on is
going to use bash
anyway yeah let's do
that there we go it's happier now
get
add uh commit give me one
second uh
switch Vim setup install script to bash
it's actually safer and I always have
bash so anyway we were using there so
you don't know you probably don't know
bash yet too much and and that's okay if
you don't this first part right here is
just checking to see if we have Vim on
the system and this check here uh it's
to checking to see if we have Vim tutor
on the system if you don't have that you
probably have something called Vim tiny
and this is just a reminder to me that I
need to do AP install bin uh Vim so
let's just describe what I mean by that
so um I believe the default tuntu server
now is to install a package called Vim
tiny and it is it does not have all the
stuff of the larger them bottom line and
so you probably want that and and you'll
probably want to do the installation for
that um uh and that's what that check is
doing right there uh this here is it
creates a a hard link I'm sorry a
symbolic link and it overrides it the F
says replace it PWD is the current
working directory wherever you're
running the script um and it takes the
vimrc file inside of this directory and
links it makes a symbolic link toome
vmrc uh this makes a directory inside of
VM
uh this should probably be-
P
um oh I know why I did
that I did that because- P is not is not
uh posix compliant but let's just do
this instead uh if you do DP it will
create theim directory and then create
the autoload directory so that's fine um
um same
here uh okay so this is the symbolic
link it says hey this plug file that I
have in this directory right here let's
make sure to put it over there now
something that I have done in the past
is make these files so they can be seen
in here if somebody were to just wander
in here they'd be like I can't see
anything right and I'm actually kind of
tempted to change this right now
um because I mean I I go back and forth
on this particular case uh these these
files were hidden you didn't see them
but do they really need to be hidden in
the setup directory right um the reason
it's that way is so that things are the
same exactly the way they would be um
but one of the things I could do to
simplify this would be to change this to
be plug dbim and then to
change uh this one to just be
bmrc and if I do that then um the only
problem with that is that like if when
I'm trying to if we if we move it let's
just do VM
RC uh to VM RC the only problem with
that is that when we go to to edit it um
it well I guess it figured it out okay
so let's do that I'm going to move the
VM
directory to
them
and um
so I mean you could actually make that
you could move Vim to
bmd however you want to do
this but this is this is just all for
you is to kind of know how to organize
your stuff right um let's see play oh
wait wait wait so we
have pwp plugin put plug. Bim
autoload oh wait wait wait wait wait
this one would be oh wait we don't even
need that anymore I don't think we need
the the
vmd find
[Music]
vmd vmd autoload plugin Vim yeah we
don't need any of that now we can just
do I mean the one reason you would do
that maybe you had other stuff you
wanted to put in
there um and so that might be a reason
to do it and I think that's probably why
I did it but I'm going to go ahead and
just move
plug uh into this directory so I'm going
to because then I don't have less files
to deal
with I'm going to put that in
here and that leaves our Vim directory
empty and we need an RMF because it's
empty because it's do got anything in it
so now we just have the two files why is
plug
executable oh no it's not executable
it's just a special file so I was it was
the same color so I was confused there
for a second so let's look at my setup
script I know I'm spending time here
like simplifying but it's worth it so
here we make the directory and then this
says to sying plug.
whatever um and so so when we run that
script that script will show you it will
actually um when you run setup it'll put
all the stuff in the right places okay
and um so I ran setup now when you do LS
L um
home.
Vim we can see we have the auto
load and we see the the Vim the plug the
Vim directory uh is pointing to the
right thing now I still you'll see
that's what the f was for so before it
was pointing to the other thing and
since I moved it now I had to rerun the
setup script so this is pointing this
shows that inside of my home directory
this is somewhat confusing people think
they have to change stuff in Etsy local
and places we'll talk about that in a
second um and you home arix rob. VM
autol vm. plug. VM and what this is is
this is lo the only plug-in manager that
matters as far as I'm concerned for for
Vim we will do a separate video on the
why you should use plug as your plug-in
manager and why you should not overly
populate stuff in your plug directory um
and as you can see in
vmrc um here I'll go find it there's the
plug
stuff um if plug is detected then load
the plugins uh again another video goes
over that but there's the use of plug
and that H that's the only thing that
has to be
pre-populated uh besides your vmrc file
and by the way let's look at the vimrc
file again here uh
vmrc and you'll see that it is now
symbolically linked to this rep here the
thing that's great about that is that if
you make a change whether you edit it by
going to
vmrc uh like this so you just want to
make a temporary change or you want to
edit it in its location here um you know
you can do that you can go ahead and and
and add that um as you can see I'm going
to have to make some get changes here
I'm going to go get add. Vim you can tab
complete
RC um git status we're going to do a
video on git as well of course um I
probably have several and then we need
to add the new files so get add plug
them uh get add memy get
status okay so I did update the setup
script so get add setup the GPT change
is a different thing I made that some
time ago so that's a different commit
get status all right so get commit
um
uh uh DM
move uh let's see
make uh them stuff easier to
find and then get push and that'll push
it up to my DOT piles I am editing on
the main tree because it's my DOT piles
otherwise I would normally not do that
status uh I'm going to go ahead and add
this other thing that I forgot to add
the other day my chat
GPT and we could say get commit uh add
uh scripts uh
GPT get push let me make sure there's
nothing in there I don't think there's a
token in there nope okay so uh get
push and really that's it my friends
I'll put the fishies on that's all
that's all there there are essentially
two files that need to be added the
vimrc file um and the Vim the plug. VM
file which goes in your autoload
directory under VM those two things
those are the only two files you need to
get going and then once you start up uh
them you'll be it'll initialize plug and
you can actually get it to download the
plugins that's a separate video we'll
talk about how to get all of the plugins
and to
uh use them and what they're for that's
a totally separate video so just those
two files and make sure you keep track
of those because you're going to
definitely want to recreate that later
so consider adop files